Hello, welcome back to the course, today we are going to continue talking about text formatting.
Let us start from this general rules of the syntax. So, for example, to type
text, we just type plain text. If we'd like to have our text in italics, then we use this single asterisk and single underscores.
If you would like to have our text in bold, then we use double asterisk or double underscores, and then we have also other options for
the syntax of our text, but I think what's most important here is how to
create a link with the text
associated with that link. So basically I put the text in the bracket, and then I put the link into parentheses, and you can see that now I have a text
with the link associated with it. When it comes to creating headers, we basically use hashtags, and the more hashtags we use,
the smaller the header becomes. And, for example, for creating this particular header
in this slide, I used two hashtags. When it comes to the creation of an unordered list,
we could first select a symbol we would like to use. For example, I would like to start from an asterisk,
or I would like to start from a plus, we could basically swap them. And then what's important when it comes to an unordered list is the spacing from
the beginning of the line. So the spacing for elements of the same list should be the same. So you can see that
the symbols here are basically on the same level, and then the symbols, like pluses here, are also, like, spaced equally from the beginning of the line.
When it comes to ordered lists or definition lists, it's very intuitive, I just start typing the numbers or the letters.
And once again, the spacing is important, the spacing from the beginning of the line.
And then for the definition lists, first I defined
that definition, what that is, so remark, term, etc. And then I write the text of the definition.
Alright, when it comes to the creation of tables, we have these vertical bars and dashes to create them.
So the number of dashes defines the width of a particular column.
And then, alignment is defined through placing colons. So basically, if the colon is placed on the right, the text is aligned to the right.
Similarly, if the colon is placed to the left, the text is aligned to the left.
By default, we have left alignment.
When it comes to embedding mathematical formulas, this can be done with LaTeX.
So, for example, we could put our formula in that two dollar signs, and then our formula will appear in the next line.
If we would like to have an inline formula, then we could use just single dollars,
and then inside the formula between them. You can see now, that
that formula is inserted inline to our text. And here, you have a link, with a math
cheat sheet, there's one hint I would like to give you. So, if you know LaTeX, then you can embed LaTeX commands in R Markdown.
But this works properly when generating PDFs, but not for HTMLs.
We could also insert slide breaks and footnotes using these three asterisks.
And we could also create footnotes and remarks. So to create a footnote or remark,
we used this bracket, and then caret, and then the number of the
footnote. When it comes to the
text input and output for embedding R: Let's just have a look. So basically here, this is how I would
write an R chunk, so you can see, if I write it in this way,
then I can see this line of text, and I can also see it in the console. So you can see that this is also written as a character in the console.
If I would like to avoid having text from the script
written, then I need to select echo parameter to be false.
Now, how can we embed a plot into our R chunk? So basically, here you can see that I
started my R chunk, then I selected the height of the plot,
and basically, I selected the background to be light gray.
And then here you can see that I just used our plot function to create that plot, and you can see that
this is something I can see now in my R Markdown document embedded.
When it comes to creation of the tables from R,
it's possible, so basically here we have this tab, which is basically a table for the species from IRIS data, and then I could create a table using this
kable function from knitr package. And here we can also customize, which particular element we would like to display in our table.
And here is a list of some chunk options.
Instead of me going through all these options, I definitely advise you to try them yourself.
Because some of them will be more useful for you, some of them will be less useful for you, but definitely,
you know, try it out, have a look, and have fun while programming.